Guide to the Jerome Moross Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Works by Jerome Moross
  - Subseries III.15: Cardinal
    - "An Episode in Vienna": manuscript in pencil., 1963, (65 pages a.ms.) (Box 11)
    - Gamma Productions, Inc. Piano score: 1) "Main Theme," published version. 2) "Waltz," published version., 1963, (3 pages bd, 5 pages bd.) (Box 11)
    - Publicity items: 1) Article by Bill Batchelor, London. 2) Review. "The American Record Guide." February 1964; page 545. 3) Film production list and program., 1963-1964, (4 pages t.ms., 1 page, 1 booklet) (Box 11)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in pencil on thin sheets with changes., 1963, (123 pages) (Box 11)
    - , Orchestral score: ozalid copy., 1963, (127 pages bd.) (Box 11)
    - Score: ozalid copies (incomplete)., 1963, (37 pages bd., 118 pages bd.) (Box 11)
    - Records: 1) "Otto Preminger presents: The Cardinal." 2) "The Cardinal: Dixieland Tango." 3) "The Cardinal: Theatre Tango." 4) "The Cardinal: U.S.A.", 1963, (4 discs) (Box 42)
  - Subseries III.16: Close Up
    - Score: ozalid copy., 1947(?), (39 pages) (Box 12)
  - Subseries III.17: Cocaine Lil'
    - American Composers Alliance, Inc. Vocal score: blue print., (8 pages) (Box 12)
  - Subseries III.18: Concerto for Flute with String Quartet
    - Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets., 1978, (61 pages a.ms.) (Box 12)
    - Scores for Parts: 1) Ozalid copy (5 parts). 2) Manuscript on thin sheets (6 parts)., 1978, (90 pages, 107 pages a.ms.) (Box 12)
    - Sorom Editions Score: solo flute and piano reduction. 1) Printed; 13 p. bd. and 45 p. bd. 2) Manuscript in pencil., 1998 copyright, (58 pages bd., 63 pages a.ms.) (Box 12)
    - Publicity items: 1) Contract (Moross and Monday Productions). 2) Collected reviews and notices (as of 24 June 1980). 3) Publicity prints (Moross as a child); 3 copies. 4) "Critic's Choice" listings in "High Fidelity," Vol. 30, No. 3: March 1980; page 82., 1975-1981, (1 page, 12 pages, 3 pages (12.5 x 12.5 in.), 1 page) (Box 12)
  - Subseries III.19: Cow in Trailer
    - Lyrics by Lynn Riggs and Ramon Naya; music by Jerome Moross 1) Playscript: carbon copy. 2) Vocal score: manuscript on thin sheets. Pages 1-58, 58-64, 71-106; 1 unidentified. 3) Vocal score "Scene 1": ozalid copy. 4) Vocal score: ozalid copy, unidentified pages., (90 pages t.ms., 102 pages, 12 pages, 104 pages, bd.) (Box 12)
      [Musical Play]
  - Subseries III.20: Creole Dance
    - To John W. Green CBS Correspondence regarding radio performance of Moross' composition., New York City, 1934, (1 page t.l.s., 1 page a.l.s.) (Box 12)
  - Subseries III.21: Culture Vultures or Rise and Fall of Picklepop (Musical farce)
    - Scenerio: "First Outline.", 196?, (21 page t.ms.) (Box 12)
  - Subseries III.22: Dance to the People
    - Esther Junger and the Dance Theatre Series of the Y.M.H.A. Program: performance includes Moross work., 1940, (4 pages) (Box 12)
  - Subseries III.23: Devil is an Ass
    Original title "The Great Lucifer"
    - John LaTouche and Jerome Moross Synopsis: carbon copy., 6, (pages t.ms. ) (Box 12)
  - Subseries III.24: Etude d'Execution Transcendente sur une Chanson Populaire Americaine Le Voyageur d'Arkansaw
    - Score: manuscript on thin sheets., (2 pages, 1 torn page) (Box 12)
  - Subseries III.25: Five Finger Exercise
    - Score: manuscript sketches in pencil., (87 pages a.ms.) (Box 13)
    - Orchestral score: ozalid copy., (89 pages) (Box 13)
      [See also compact disc: "Valley of Gwangi." (Box 47)]
  - Subseries III.26: Flossy
    - 1) Lyrics with notes in pencil. 2) Publicity: newspaper clipping from Daily News., n.d.; 4 May 1963, (24 pages t.ms., 1 page) (Box 13)
    - Score, Parts I-IX: manuscript in pencil., (137 pages a.ms.) (Box 13)
    - Synopsis, carbon copies. 1) "Act 1"; 6 p. 2) "The First Lady"; 7 p. 3) "The First Lady" with corrections; 7 p. 4) "Flossie: An Outline for a Musical"; 9 p. 5) "Flossie: An Outline of a Work for the Musical Theatre"; 2 copies of 11 p., (51 pages t.ms.) (Box 13)
    - Vocal scores. 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, Acts I-IX. 2) Ozalid copy, Acts I-IX. 3) Ozalid copy., (105 pages, 67 pages, 32 pages bd.) (Box 13)
  - Subseries III.27: For Joshua and Aaron
    - Clarinet part: 1) Manuscript in ink on thin sheet; 1 p. 2) Ozalid copies; 4 p. Score for clarinet and piano: 3) Manuscript in pencil; 2 p. 4) Manuscript in ink on thin sheets; 3 p. 5) Ozalid copy; 3 p., (13 pages) (Box 13)
      [Duet for clarinet and piano]
  - Subseries III.28: Forget Me Not
    - Orchestral and vocal score Movements I-V: manuscript in pencil on thin sheets., (43 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 13)
    - Scores for Movements I-V: 1) Manuscript for 4 parts (strings) in pen. 2) Ozalid copies of orchestral and vocal score; 4 copies of 43 p., (57 pages a.ms., 172 pages bd.) (Box 13)
    - Scenerio: carbon copy., (7 pages t.ms.) (Box 13)
    - Vocal score "Some Day" (song): 1) Manuscript on thin sheets in pencil. 2) Ozalid copy., (3 pages a.ms.s., 3 pages) (Box 13)
    - Video tape recording: "When I Grow Up.", (1 cassette) (Box 41)
    - Record: "J. Moross: Music from Forget Me Not.", (1 disc) (Box 42)
  - Subseries III.29: Frankie and Johnny
    - Orchestral score: 1) Ozalid copies; 194 pages each. 2) Notes by Moross., 1938, (2 vol., 2 pages ) (Box 14)
      [Ballet]
    - Orchestral score: reduced negative transparencies; not in sequence., 1938, (194 pages) (Box 14)
    - Orchestral score: enlarged photocopy with composer's corrections., 1938, (194 pages) (Box 242)
      [Gift 1992]
    - Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets., 1938, (194 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 242)
    - Orchestral score: ozalid copy., 1938, (194 pages bd.) (Box 242)
    - Publicity items. 1) Newspaper clippings collected with a personal memo from "Tom." 2) Season flyer from Chicago Ballet (1978). 3) Book: "Les Ballet Americains" by authors including Ruth Page (autographed), Jose Limon, and Bentley Stone with photographs by Serge Lido., 1945-1978, (9 pages a.s., 4 pages bd., 1 vol. s.) (Box 14)
    - Newspaper clippings: photocopies., n.d., 1933-1982, (66 pages) (Box 14)
    - Periodical clippings: 1) "Saturday Review," page 52. 2) "Time," page 88. 3) "Musical America," page 19. 4) Clipping with signature of Mike Snell., 1945-1965, (1 folder) (Box 14 [COPIES])
    - Programs: Dance Theatre of Harlem; Cincinnati Ballet Company; Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre; Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo; Les Ballet des Champs-Elysees., 1945-1982, (23 programs) (Box 14)
    - Score (22 parts): manuscript on transparencies., 1938, (256 pages) (Box 15)
    - Orchestral score: early version with corrections and additions by Moross., 1938, (168 pages bd.) (Box 15)
    - Orchestral score: miniature photocopy of early version., 1938, (168 pages) (Box 15)
    - Score for two pianos: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets. 2) Ozalid copy., 1938, (56 pages a.ms. s., 55 pages bd.) (Box 15)
    - Vocal score "Women's Trio"(for 2 sopranos and 1 alto): manuscript in pencil., 1938, (12 pages a.ms.) (Box 15)
    - Vocal score "Women's trio": 1) Reduced ozalid; 5 copies of 12 p. bd. 2) Negative ozalid. 3) Reduced negative photostat., 1938, (5 vol., 12 pages, 12 pages) (Box 15)
    - Record: "Jerome Moross: The Scandalous Life of Frankie and Johnny." Vienna Symphony Orchestra. Walter Hendl, Dean Dixon, conductors., (1 disc) (Box 42)
    - Parts (22): new master parts with all corrections. Receipts for writing services (3)., 1938, (256 pages, 3 folders) (Box 45)
      [Gift 1991]
  - Subseries III.30: General Armchair
    - 1) Playscript. 2) Score: manuscript; signed; 3) Score in copyist's hand., 1943, (20 pages t.ms., 8 pages ms.s., 5 pages) (Box 16)
      [Radio Play]
  - Subseries III.31: Gentlemen, Be Seated!
    - New York City Opera Company Cast list; 7 copies., 10 October 1963, (7 pages) (Box 16)
      [A Musical Entertainment in Two Acts]
    - Opening night telegrams to Jerome and Hazel Moross., 9-11 October 1963, (36 telegrams) (Box 16)
    - Playscript: early draft with corrections and changes., 1963, (71 page t.ms.) (Box 16)
    - Playscript: drafts with many changes and additions and letters from collaborator Edward Eager., 1963, (184 pages t.ms.) (Box 16)
    - Playscript: later copy with changes., 1963, (100 pages t.ms.) (Box 16)
    - Playscript: final copy., 1963, (90 pages t.ms.) (Box 16)
    - Publicity: 1) Playbill. 2) Press release from The Playwrights' Company., 1963, (1 program, 2 pages) (Box 16)
    - Publicity: newspaper clippings., n.d.,15 April 1955-11 October 1963, (12 pages) (Box 16)
    - Publicity: periodical clippings. 1) "Saturday Review." 26 Oct 1963. 2) "Show." Jan 1964., 1963, (3 pages, 3 pages) (Box 16)
    - Orchestral scores: reduced ozalid copies. 1) "Grand March." 2) "In the Sunny Old South." 3) "The Freedom Train." 4) "Waltzing in the Shadow." 5) "Fare You Well." 6) "The Dome." 7) "Picnic at Manassas." 8) "Mockingbird." 9) [untitled] 10) "The Ballad of Belle Boyd." 11) "'Mancipation." 12) "It Isn't a Gentleman's War." 13) "The Contraband Ball." 14) "Gentlemen, Be Seated." 15) "All Quiet on the Potomac." [no designated 16] 17) "Mr. Brady Takes a Photograph." 18) "I Can't Remember." 19) "From Atlanta to the Sea.", 1963, (988 pages, 18 folders) (Box 17)
    - Orchestral scores: manuscripts. Discarded sheets; 8 p. 1) "Grand March"; 51 p. 2) "In the Sunny Old South"; 31 p. 3) "Freedom Train"; 38 p. 4) "Waltzing in the Shadows"; 140 p. 5) "Fare You Well"; 28 p. 6) "The Dome"; 43 p. [no designated 7], 1963, (7 folders) (Box 243)
      [Complete manuscript: 988 pages a.ms.]
    - Orchestral scores: manuscripts. 8) "Mockingbird"; 14 p. [no designated 9] 10) "The Ballad of Belle Boyd"; 88 p. 11) "'Mancipation"; 24 p. 12) "It Isn't a Gentleman's War"; 55 p. 13) "Contraband Ball"; 115 p. 14) "Gentlemen, Be Seated!"; 26 p. 1963, (6 folders) (Box 244)
    - Orchestral scores: manuscripts. 15) "All Quiet on the Potomac"; 40 p. [no designated 16] 17) "Mr. Brady Takes a Photograph"; 88 p. 18) "I Can't Remember"; 26 p., 1963, (3 folders) (Box 245)
    - Orchestral scores: manuscripts. 19) "From Atlanta to the Sea"; 132 p. 20) "What Has Become of Beauty?"; 47 p. 21) "Have You Seen Him?"; 29 p. 22) "Grand Finale"; 27 p., 1963, (4 folders) (Box 246)
    - Stage design. 1) Watercolor painting, signed by William Pitkin. 2) Watercolor and ink painting for stage curtain; signed and inscribed to Moross by William Pitkin., 1963, (2 paintings s.) (Box Map Case 14-14-7)
    - Piano/vocal scores, Act 1: 1) Songs 1-13. Ozalid copy with changes and additions. 2) Extra #13 "The Contraband Ball," ozalid copy with changes. 3) "Dialogue IX- page 1" with memo., 1963, (1 vol. bd., 39 pages bd., 2 1 page t.ms.; 1 page a.ms.) (Box 247)
      [Stamped "New York City Opera."]
    - Piano/vocal score, Act II: 1) Ozalid copy with changes in pencil. 2) #17 "Mr. Brady Takes a Photograph.", 1963, (138 pages bd., 24 pages bd.) (Box 247)
      [Stamped "New York City Opera Company."]
    - Ozalid copies in 4 folios, duplicates with additions in pencil. 1) Act I: "Grand March"; 17 p. 2) "The Freedom Train"; 17 p. 3) "The Contraband Ball"; 39 p. 4) "What Has Become of Beauty"; 12 p., 1963, (85 pages bd.) (Box 247)
    - Vocal score: Act I and Act II. Ozalid copy in 23 folios., 1963, (355 pages bd.) (Box 248)
    - Parts for musical numbers 1-12. Manuscripts on transparancies (with changes) and copies in blueprint. 1) "Grand March," manuscript. 2) "Grand March," copies. 3) "In the Sunny Old South," manuscript. 4) "In the Sunny Old South," copies. 5) "The Freedom Train," manuscript. 6) "The Freedom Train," copies. 7) "Waltzing in the Shadows," manuscript. 8) "Waltzing in the Shadows," copies. 9) "Fare You Well," manuscript. 10) "Fare You Well," copies. 11) "The Dome," manuscript. 12) "The Mocking Bird," copies [no manuscript]. 13) "Ballad of Belle Boyd," manuscript. 14) "Ballad of Belle Boyd," copies. 15) "'Mancipation," manuscript [no copy]. 16) "This Isn't a Gentleman's War," manuscript. 17) "[It's Not] a Gentleman's War," copies., 1963, (17 folders) (Box 18)
    - Parts for musical numbers 13-22. Manuscripts on transparancies (with changes) and blueprint copies. 1) "The Contraband Ball," manuscript. 2) "The Contraband Ball," copies. 3) "Gentlemen, Be Seated!" manuscript. 4) "All Quiet on the Potomac," manuscript. 5) "All Quiet on the Potomac," copies. 6) "Mr. Brady Takes a Photograph," manuscript. 7) "Mr. Brady Takes a Photograph," copies. 8) "I Can't Remember," manuscript. 9) "I Can't Remember," copy. 10) "From Atlanta to the Sea," manuscript. 11) "From Atlanta to the Sea," copies. 12) "What Has Become of Beauty?" manuscript. 13) "What Has Become of Beauty?" copies.14) "Have You Seen Him?" manuscript. 15) "Have You Seen Him?" copies. 16) "Grand Finale," manuscript. 17) "Grand Finale," copies., 1963, (17 folders) (Box 19)
    - Curtain design: 8 photocopies of 1 page., 1963, (8 pages) (Box 20)
      [See also Map Case 14-14-7.]
    - Stage design: "The Dome." Watercolor and wash drawing signed by artist William Pitkin., 1963, (1 painting s.) (Box 20)
    - Vocal score Act I: manuscript on thin sheets., 1963, (212 pages a.ms.) (Box 20)
    - Vocal score, Act II: manuscript on thin sheets., 1963, (140 pages a.ms.) (Box 20)
    - Vocal score: manuscript on thin sheets (revised pages)., 1963, (11 pages a.ms.) (Box 20)
    - Vocal score: ozalid copies in 15 folios., 1963, (212 pages) (Box 20)
    - Records. "Gentlemen Be Seated!": 1) "Act I, Part 1" and "Act I, Part 2"; 2 copies. 2) "Act 1, Part 3" and "Act I, Part 4"; 2 copies. 3) "Act II, Part 1"and "Act II, Part 2"; 2 copies., 1963, (6 discs) (Box 42)
    - Score (Parts) "Picnic at Manassas, No. 7": 1) Xerox copy. 2) List of corrections., 1963, (62 pages, 3 pages) (Box 47)
  - Subseries III.32: Golden Apple
    - Director's score: ozalid copy with notes and changes., 1954, (325 pages bd.) (Box 21)
    - Director's score: ozalid copy with notes and changes., 1954, (157 pages bd., 191 pages bd.) (Box 21)
    - Director's score: ozalid copy with notes and changes., 1954, (157 pages bd., 191 pages bd.) (Box 21)
    - Orchestral score, Act I: manuscript on thin sheets; p. 3-105., 1954, (102 pages a.ms.) (Box 22)
    - Orchestral score, Act II: manuscript on thin sheets., 1954, (65 pages a.ms.) (Box 22)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in ink on thin sheets., 1954, (395 pages a.ms.) (Box 22)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in pencil on thin sheets., 1954, (197 pages a.ms.) (Box 22)
    - Orchestral score: ozalid copies with changes and additions on thin manuscript sheets in pencil., 1954, (251 pages a.ms.) (Box 22)
    - Orchestral score, Act 1 (1): ozalid copy with changes; p. 4-100., 1954, (96 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 1 (2): ozalid copy with changes; p. 141-284., 1954, (143 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 1 (3): ozalid copy with changes; p. 285-391C., 1954, (108 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 1 (4): ozalid copy with changes; p. 391-480., 1954, (89 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 1 (5): ozalid copy with changes; p. 481-530., 1954, (51 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 2 (1): ozalid copy with changes; p. 1-116., 1954, (116 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 2 (2): ozalid copy with changes; p. 117-197., 1954, (80 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 2 (3): ozalid copy with changes; p. 198-311., 1954, (113 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 2 (4): ozalid copy with changes; p. 312-460., 1954, (148 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act 2 (5): ozalid copy with changes; p. 460-533., 1954, (73 pages bd.) (Box 23)
    - Orchestral score, Act I (1): ozalid copy with changes; p. 2-100., 1954, (99 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act I (2): ozalid copy with changes; p. 141-284., 1954, (143 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act I (3): ozalid copy with changes; p. 285-390., 1954, (105 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act I (4): ozalid copy with changes; p. 391-506., 1954, (115 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act I (5): ozalid copy with changes; p. 507-595., 1954, (88 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act II (1): ozalid copy with changes; p. 1-106., 1954, (105 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act II (2): ozalid copy with changes; p. 107-223., 1954, (106 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act II (3): ozalid copy with changes; p. 224-353., 1954, (129 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act II (4): ozalid copy with changes; p.354-471., 1954, (117 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act II (5): ozalid copy with changes; p. 472-569., 1954, (97 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score, Act II (6), "New Finale": ozalid copy with changes; p. 533-569., 1954, (36 pages bd.) (Box 24)
    - Orchestral Score, Act I: ozalid copy; p. 1-100 (series incomplete)., 1954, (40 pages (double sided)) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score, Act II: ozalid copy with changes and additions; p. 1-116., 1954, (116 pages bd.) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score, Act II: ozalid copy with changes; p. 117-197. 1954, (80 pages bd.) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score, Act II: ozalid copy with changes; p.198-311. 1954, (113 pages bd.) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score, Act II: ozalid copy with changes and additions; p. 312-439. 1954, (127 pages bd.) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score, Act II: ozalid copy with changes and additions; p. 440-509. 1954, (69 pages bd.) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score: miscellaneous pages with changes and additions; previously torn from binding., 1954, (15 pages (double sided)) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score: miscellaneous pages, blueprint and ozalid copies., 1954, (519 pages) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score: ozalid negatives., 1954, (4 pages) (Box 25)
    - Orchestral score: discarded manuscript on thin sheets. Identified "55D" and "162-163.", 1954, (2 pages a.ms.) (Box 249)
    - Orchestral score, Act I: ozalid copy with changes; p. 1-231., 1954, (230 pages bd.) (Box 249)
    - Orchestral score, Act I: ozalid copy with changes; p. 232-431, 1954, (199 pages bd.) (Box 249)
    - Orchestral score, Act I: ozalid copy with changes; p. 432-530., 1954, (98 pages bd.) (Box 249)
    - Orchestral score, Act I: ozalid copy with changes; p. 531-595., 1954, (64 pages bd.) (Box 249)
    - Orchestral score, Act II: ozalid copies with changes. 1) Pages 1-40 and 350; 41 p. bd. 2) Pages 1-143; 143 p. bd. 3) Pages 144-248; 104 p. bd. 4) Pages 249-411; 162 p. bd. 5) Pages 412-499; 87 p. bd. 6) Pages 533-567 - "New Finale"; 34 p. bd., 1954, (6 folios) (Box 250)
    - Orchestral score, Act II: reverse blueprint (ink); p. 1-38., 1954, (38 pages) (Box 250)
    - Vocal score: 1) Manuscript in pencil on thin sheets; pages identified: 321, 322, 325, 326, 328; 5 p. 2) Handwritten memo: "Photograph, original vocal score, Pages 318-319-320"; 1 p., 1954, (6 pages a.ms.) (Box 250)
    - Bill Hargate, visual artist. Stage design: watercolor painting. 1954, (1 painting s.) (Box 250)
    - Publicity poster. York Playhouse: 1st Ave. at 64th St., New York City., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 250)
    - Playscript: carbon draft with changes and additions., 1954, (97 pages bd.) (Box 26)
    - Playscript: mimeograph copy., 1954, (101 pages bd.) (Box 26)
    - Playscript: draft with changes and additions., 1954, (92 pages bd.) (Box 26)
    - Playscript, Act I: manuscript (early draft) on thin sheets with handwritten corrections., 1954, (85 pages t.ms./a.ms.) (Box 26)
    - Playscript, Act II: manuscript (early draft) on thin sheets., 1954, (72 pages t.ms.) (Box 26)
    - Playscript: miscellaneous handwritten notes and sketches., 1954, (53 pages a.ms.) (Box 26)
    - Playscript: miscellaneous draft., 1954, (46 pages t.ms.) (Box 26)
    - Playscript: carbon drafts., 1954, (62 pages ) (Box 26)
    - Production papers including cast list, contract, correspondence with Lucy Kroll agency, statements, petition to Ford Foundation., 1954, (31 pages ) (Box 26)
    - Production papers: statements., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 26)
    - Publicity clippings: newspapers., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 26 [COPIES])
    - Publicity: 11 programs. Cast/production biographies., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 26)
    - Publicity: newspaper clippings., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 27 [COPIES])
    - Publicity: periodical clippings., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 27 [COPIES])
    - Publicity: photographs of Moross and production shots; various sizes., 1954, (30 photographs) (Box 27)
    - Publicity: programs. 1954, (56 items) (Box 27)
    - Embossed scrapbook: no contents., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 27)
    - Empty folder: marked "vocal score- ozalid copy bound, 2 vol.", 1954, (1 folder) (Box 28Askpatrick)
    - Vocal score: manuscript in pencil; miscellaneous pages., 1954, (38 pages a.ms.) (Box 28)
    - Vocal score: manuscript on thin sheets; miscellaneous pages., 1954, (26 pages a.ms.) (Box 28)
    - Vocal score, Act I: manuscript in pencil., 1954, (178 pages a.ms.) (Box 28)
    - Vocal score, Act II: manuscript in pencil., 1954, (167 pages a.ms.) (Box 28)
    - Vocal score, Act I: ozalid copy., 1954, (149 pages) (Box 29)
    - Vocal score: ozalid negatives., 1954, (155 pages) (Box 29)
    - Vocal score, Act II: ozalid copy., 1954, (45 pages bd.) (Box 29)
    - Vocal score: ozalid copy; misecellaneous pages., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 29)
    - Vocal score: printed songs; 7 pages each., 1954, (4 volumes, 28 pages bd.) (Box 29)
    - Vocal score, Act I: ozalid copy; miscellaneous pages., 1954, (1 folder) (Box 251)
    - Microfilm. 1) "Orchestral score: Act I." 2) "Vocal Score.", (2 boxes/reels) (Box 40)
    - Record: "The Golden Apple." Original cast album: Phoenix Theatre production., (1 disc) (Box 42)
    - Compact disc: "The Golden Apple: A Musical Play." Hugh Ross, musical director., 1997 copyright., (1 disc) (Box 47)
    - Piano conductor score: "computerized score.", 1954, (388 pages) (Box 48)
    - Piano conductor score., 1954, (393 pages bd.) (Box 48)
    - Playscript., 1954, (80 pages bd.) (Box 48)
  - Subseries III.33: Guns and Castanets
    - Vocal and piano score: ozalid copy., 1939, (46 pages) (Box 30)
      [Two songs from the ballet]
    - Two songs from the Ballet. 1) Photostat of miniature orchestral score; p. 101-111. 2) Vocal and piano score: manuscript, signed. 3) Vocal and piano score: ozalid copy., 1939, (10 pages, 5 pages ms.s., 5 pages) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.34: Gunsmoke
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in pencil. 1) "The Corral." 2) "The Horse Theft." 3) "Kitty." 4) "Jeff." 5) "Riding." 6) "Thataway." 7) "The Shark." 8) "In the Bushes." 9) "The Captive." 10) "Kurch." 11) "Back at the Ranch." 12) "Chief Quick Knife." 13) "Farewell.", (26 pages) (Box 43)
  - Subseries III.35: Have Gun Will Travel
    - Conductor's score: manuscript., (33 pages) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.36: I Hear America Singing
    Text adapted from Walt Whitman
    - Vocal score: 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy., 1940, (8 pages a.ms.s., 8 pages) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.37: In Darkness that Surrounds Us
    - 1) Piano score: ozalid copy; 3 p. 2) Vocal score: ozalid copy; 3 p., (6 pages) (Box 30)
      [Hymn]
  - Subseries III.38: In Memory of a Hero
    - 1) Piano score: manuscript draft; signed. 2) Piano score: manuscript in copyist's hand. 3) Playscript: mimeograph copy., 1943, (3 pages a.ms.s., 3 pages ms., 22 pages t.ms.) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.39: Inventions for Flute, Oboe and Bassoon
    - Score: 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed., (4 pages a.ms.s., 2 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.40: Jabberwocky
    Words by Lewis Carroll
    - Vocal score: 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy., (6 pages a.ms.s., 6 pages) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.41: Jayhawkers